Hello.
你们好
I come from outside the wall,
我来自围墙之外
where we have all but destroyed each other.
在那儿 人们相互摧残
We designed you city as an experiment.
把你们的城市设计成实验室
And we believe it is the only way to recover the humanity we have lost.
是因为坚信这是重拾人性的唯一途径
And we created Factions to ensure peace.
我们创建了派系来维护和平
But we believe there will be those among you
但我们也相信 你们当中肯定
who will transcend these factions,
有人能超越这些派系
these will be the Divergent.
他们将是分歧者
They are the true purpose of this experiment,
是这场实验的真正目的
they are vital to humanity survival.
对人类的存亡至关重要
If you are watching this now, then at least one of you is proof
如果你们正在看这段视频 说明至少有一个人
that our experiment has succeeded.
证明了实验室成功的
The time has come
是时候从
for you to emerge from your isolation and rejoin us.
你们封闭的城市里走出来了
On Evelyn's orders: This gate is now closed!
奉伊芙琳之令 马上关闭城门
We've allowed you to believe that you’re the last of us,
我们曾让你们相信自己是最后的幸存者
but you’re not.
其实不是
Mankind waits for you with hope, beyond the Wall.
其他人类正在围墙外满怀希望地等待着你们
ALLEGIANT
分歧者3：忠诚世界
We're almost there.
我们快到了
Yeah, I'm right behind you.
对 我在你后面
What are you, afraid of heights?
我说你不会恐高吧
No. Who told you that?
不 谁跟你说的
Sometimes when I look past the wall,
有时候我朝围墙外面看
I think that I can see something out there.
感觉自己能看到外面的东西
Do you?
你呢
No. I don't.
我 看不到
Maybe you need to look harder.
也许你得看仔细点儿
I am looking.
我正看着呢
I'm just not seeing what you see.
可还是什么都看不到
When it's right in front of your face, you will.
如果在眼前 你就看到了
You sure we're going to do this?
我们真的要离开吗
Yeah.
对
People of Chicago,
芝加哥的全体公民
I know you are curious about what's beyond the wall,
我知道你们很好奇围墙外有什么
but sometimes walls are there to protect us.
但有的时候围墙是在保护我们
Remember, the founders were the ones who divided us into Factions.
记住 正式那些创建者把我们划分成了若干派系
So, until we know their intentions, the wall must stay closed.
所以在我们不知道他们的真实目的前城门必须关闭
Jeanine is dead.
珍宁已经死了
Today, we begin the trials of her conspirators.
今天 我们要开始审判她的同谋者以此纪念芝加哥翻开了新的一页
Put the traitors on trial, close down the gate.
审判叛徒 关闭城门
Didn't take her long to make the same mistakes as Jeanine.
没想到 她这么快就走上了珍宁的老路
I need to talk to her.
我得跟他谈谈
I still think I can bring her around.
我想我能劝他回头
But that doesn't change anything, right?.
但那改变不了任何事
No.
不
I need you to get somethings for me.
我要你帮我弄点儿东西
Just this?
就这个
You sure you don't want the sun and moon as well?
确定不再摘个太阳月亮什么的
- I know it's a lot. - It's impossible.
我知道这很困难   简直是不可能
- So? - So, I'll make it happen.
所以  所以只有我能搞定
Well. Hello, ladies.
你们好 女士们
Where are we going? Can I come?
要去哪儿  能一起吗
- Give it up, Peter. - Why so hostile!
滚远点 皮特   太不友好了
There's no faction. We can be friends, right?
派系都没了 我们能成朋友了  对吗
Can't we all just get along?
难道就不能相亲相爱吗
Tris.
翠丝
Your should be up there with all the other leaders of the city.
你应该上去跟其他领导者在一起
No, it's not me. I don't want to make the rules.
不 我可不想  去制定什么规矩
Great leaders don't seek power, they're called by necessity.
伟大的领导者从不追逐权利 他们被社会需求所召唤
They need you.
人们需要你
Look at me! Look at me, traitor!
看着我  你这个叛徒
- You're going to die in there! - Back up.
后退 准备好去死了吗  后退
You're going to die in there!
准备去死了吗
Move!
快走
Sit tight.
待在这儿
We all find ourselves on new ground.
我们都在新环境中找到了自己
I dedicated my life to seeking the truth, but under Jeanine, it passed me by.
我毕生的志愿就是追寻真相  但珍宁却让我错过了它
And for that, I humbly apologize.
为此 我真诚想诸位道歉
But my personal failure has only strengthened my resolve to make things right.
但是我失败的教训 更坚定了我纠正自己错误的决心
While the Faction of Candor may no longer exist,
即使现在诚实派不复存在了
I want everyone to know that I will not stop leading the pursuit of honesty,
我也想让大家知道 我不会停下追寻真相的脚步
as we rebuild our city.
让我们携起手来 重建家园
- Yay! - Yay!
好 好
Let the trials begin! Justice will be done!
审判现在开始  让我们来伸张正义
- Yay! - Yay!
好 好
Here.
来吧
May the truth set you free.
愿真相让你解脱
There's no doubt, Max, that you helped Jeanine take over Chicago,
毫无疑问 你协助珍宁接管了芝加哥
and exert brutal control over it's citizens.
对人们进行了残忍的控制
So, my only question to you is this.
我唯一想问的就是你觉得
Did you feel justified in murdering people in support of her regime?
屠杀人民去支持她的政权是否正确
Absolutely.
当然正确
People are sheep. They need a shepherd to guide them.
人民是绵羊 他们需要牧羊人引导
And when they resist, they're slaughtered.
如果他们反抗 就该被杀
Monster.
We should slaughter you!
我们应该杀了你
Kill him! Kill him!
杀了他 杀了他
- Kill him! - Don't kill him!
杀了他 不要杀他
- Let him live! - Kill him!
别杀他   杀了他
- Let him live! - Kill him now!
Rise above it.
理智点
You can't do this, stop it!
你们不能这样做 快停下来
Let him live! We're better than this!
别杀他 我们跟那些杀人犯不一样
Rise above it.
理智点
Jeanine!
珍宁
Jeanine is dead!
珍宁已经死了
Let's not keep her spirit alive.
我们不能再重蹈覆辙了
- Kill him! - Let him live!
杀了他 别杀他
What are you going to do? They need an answer.
现在怎么办 得给他们个交代
This is an execution.
这是一场杀戮
No. This is a trial.
不  这是一场审判
And I yield, to the wishes of the people.
我服从全体公民的意愿
It is time, that we break from the past!
是时候打破历史的牢笼
- Yay! - Yay!
好
You need to die!
杀了他
I don't want to die.
我还不想死
Neither did your sheep.
你杀的人也不想
Yeah.
太棒了
There was a time I would have said: I leave you with love, not malice.
过去我说过  我愿你们活在爱里 而不是恨里
That time has passed.
看来过去已经过去了
- Kill her! - Traitor!
Kill her! Kill her!
Traitor!
Get out! Out! Get out! Out!
出去
Get out! Out!
Beatrice! I'm sorry!
碧翠丝 对不起
You incited a mob. Good luck controlling them.
你煽动了民众 但愿你能掌控得住
Beatrice, please! Don't let them kill me!
碧翠丝 求你了 别让他们杀了我
Beatrice! No!
碧翠丝  不
Beatrice!
碧翠丝
What the hell did you think you're doing? We need to show a united front.
你知道你在做什么吗 我们得表现得团结一致
Especially, since Tris refuses to stand with us.
尤其是翠丝拒绝跟我们同一阵营之后
- I'm not going to tell Tris what to do. - Well, you need to try!
我不会告诉她 她该干什么  你得试着跟她说
Do you really think that you can stop people leaving this city?
你真的认为自己能阻止人们离开这座城市吗
The wall's on total lock down, my soldiers have orders.
城门现在已经锁上了 我的士兵们听从我的
No one gets out.
没人能出去
Why did you go to war with Jeanine,
你为什么要跟珍宁开战
if you were just going to become her?
难道只是想变成她
Leaders need to make tough decisions to protect their people.
领导者们为了保护人民需要做出艰难的决定
You'll understand that when you take over from me.
等你继承了我的位置自然就会明白了
I'm doing this for you.
我这都是为了你
You know, it might not be the best time to leave.
现在可能不是离开的最佳时机
I know, but we can't be here for every fight.
那也不能待在这儿解决所有冲突
And the message said to come out and meet the rest of the world .
信息里也说要走出去面对新世界
Yet, we know absolutely nothing about the people who sent it.
可我们对传递信息的人一无所知
Aren't you curious to find out?
那你就不想把她找出来吗
What about our home?
我们的家园怎么办
I don't think our home exist any more.
我觉得我们的家园已经不复存在了
Maybe the way to help Chicago is climb beyond the wall.
也许走出去反而能够帮到芝加哥
What if there's nothing out there? What If there is nothing left?
可万一外面什么都没有 荒芜一片呢
I can live with that if you are with me, but I can not live without trying.
只要你在我就能活下去 但你必须得让我试一试
You know, it's Caleb's trial tomorrow.
你知道明天要审凯莱布吧
Yeah, I know.
是 我知道
I don't owe him anything.
可我没觉得有什么欠他的
No. No, you don't.
没错  你不欠他
I'm going to deal with this one.
我来处理这个人
Do you think I'm asking your permission?
你觉得我是在请求你吗
No, please. No, Four. No!
不 求你了 老四 不要
Four. Four.
老四 求你了
Please don't kill me! I'm sorry!
别杀我  对不起
Four, I'm sorry!
老四 对不起
You tried to kill your own sister, Caleb. You brought this on yourself.
连自己亲妹妹都想杀  你这是作死
I'm sorry, for everything.
对不起  我向你道歉
Come on. We're going up.
快点 我们上去
Come on. Come on.
快点
- Beatrice? - Walk slowly.
碧翠丝 慢点儿走
Hey!
嘿
All Erudite prisoners are suppose to be locked in the cages.
所有博学派的犯人都应关在牢里
Stop!
站住
I can handle this one myself.
我自己能处理这个人
Bring him in!
带他们进来
You can come out now, Caleb.
你现在能出来了
Thank you, Four. Thank you.
谢谢你 老四 谢谢
Don't thank me. It's your sister's idea.
不用谢我 是你妹妹的主意
You saved me?
你救了我
It's what you do for family.
这才是家人该做的
Get in the car.
上车吧
I knew it.
我就知道
Hey, partners.
嘿 伙计们
What are you doing, Peter? Get out of here.
你们在这干什么 皮特 离开这儿
Yes, that's what I'm doing, I'm getting out of here.
没错 我正准备要离开这儿
Look, I don't want to be here when your crazy mom
听着 在你妈妈肆意妄为的时候我可不想留在这儿
goes around killing everybody who used to work for Jeanine, okay?
她会整死所有为珍宁做过事的人
Look, I can join you guys or I could...
听着 要么现在就让我加入你们要么我就
Yell: Help! Help! Help! They're getting away!
大喊 救命 他们要跑了 嚷嚷什么 消停会行吗
Get in the car, Peter. Get in the car.
上车 皮特 上车
- That's what I'm saying. - Get in the car.
就等这句话呢  上车
Thank you.
谢谢
What's up, Caleb?
还好吗 凯莱布
Yeah!
没错
We want the truth!
我们要听真相
He's dead. Yeah. Hurry up and kill him.
他死定了 对 快杀了他
Justice for all!
伸张正义
You do have a plan, right?
你已经有计划了是吧
I didn't hear anything about a prisoner transfer.
我没接到任何转移犯人的通知
Well, you're hearing it from me.
我刚刚通知过你
Let me see your movement order.
请出示转移令
I got it! Right here!
在这儿呢 在我这儿
I got everything. So, open the gate.
这是转移令 把门打开
One more, come on. Come on, one more. Yeah!
再来一个 快点儿 好 埃德加
Tobias Eaton took Caleb Prior out of his cage.
托比亚斯·伊顿把凯莱布·普勒尔带走了
Come on. Let's go, now.
快点儿 我们走 快
Come on! Let's do some more!
快点儿 再审几个
You a statue?
你是雕塑吗
Open the gate.
快开门
Have they come through here?
他们从这儿走的
Let's get out of here.
我们离开这儿
They're getting away.
他们跑了
Tobias Eaton is abetting Caleb Prior's escape. That makes him a traitor.
托比亚斯·伊顿带着凯莱布·普勒尔逃跑了 他也成了反叛者
Shoot to kill.
杀了他
No body goes over that wall. We have our orders.
任何人不得翻越围墙 这是命令
You Ready?
好了吗
Yeah.
好了
Not the same as reading in the books, huh?
跟书本上学的不太一样
okay, coast is clear.
好了 没有危险
It's time to see what's out there.
是时候走出去了
Okay. On me.
好的 跟紧我
Shit. Release now!
该死 发射 抓钩
I got him.
我去帮他
I'm sorry, Four.
抱歉 老四
Come on. Come on.
快点
- Ahhhh! - CHRISTINA !
- I'm okay. - That part of the plan, Stiff?
没事 这也是计划的一部分
Evelyn electrified the fence.
伊芙琳给围栏通了电
We did it.
我们成功了
Tori.
托莉
Tori. Tori! Tori!
Okay, Tori.
天哪 托莉
Come on, we got to go. Come on!
快点儿 我们得离开这儿
No! Tori!
不 托莉
Tori.
托莉
Get in the car!
上车
Alright, let's go.
好了 我们走
Come on. This way!
快点儿 这边
Holy shit.
我的天哪
What happened here?
这儿发生了什么
Didn't exactly sent out a welcome committee for you, Stiff.
根本没为你准备欢迎仪式 僵尸人
Shut up, Peter.
闭嘴  皮特
Humanity welcomes you with hope. What humanity?
人类满怀希望地欢迎你们 人在那儿呢
This hole looks radioactive.
这个水坑看起来好像又放射性
Or at least it was so in the last 200 years.
至少得有200年了
Meaning what exactly?
这能说明什么问题
Somebody seriously messed up the world.
有人毁了这个世界
Shit.
该死
Great. Now the sky is bleeding.
真给力 天空都流血了
This way!
这边走
Come on, let's go!
快点儿  我们走
Now, come on.
跟紧了
This is fun. I'm glad we did this.
真好玩 把自己给玩了
What if there's nothing else out there?
万一什么都没有呢
There has to be.
一定会有的
I'm scared.
我害怕
Yeah, I think that's a good thing.
我想  这是正常反应
You guys hear that?
听到了吗
- It's an engine. - Someone's coming for us.
是引擎 有人来找我们了
- It's Edgar. Go, go! - Come on!
是埃德加 快跑 快
Go, go! Turn back, go!
快 快跑 那边跑
Hollis! No! Hollis!
霍利斯 不 霍利斯
Who, what is this?
天哪 这是 这是什么
Don't be afraid, there's nothing to worry about.
别害怕 不用担心
You're safe now.
你们现在安全了
Welcome, Four.
欢迎你 老四
Tris Prior, it's an honor to meet you.
普勒尔很荣幸见到你
How do you know our names?
你怎么知道我名字
What the?
什么情况
Oh oh.
Welcome to the future. We've been waiting for you.
欢迎来到你们的未来 我们一直在等你们
Our plasma globes will protect you from the toxicity.
等离子球会把你们和有毒的环境隔离开
Hey.
嘿
- We're going to be okay. - Yeah.
我们现在安全了  对
Look.
看啊
This is incredible.
不可思议
This is insane!
简直太疯狂了
Get out.
天哪 超赞
It's Tris.
她是翠丝
Welcome, to the Bureau of Genetic Alter. My name is Matthew.
欢迎你们来到基因福利局 我是马修
Now, let's get you into decontamination.
现在 你们将被送进净化区 他们从芝加哥来
That's her, Beatrice Prior. She made it.
那个就是她 翠丝普勒尔 她终于来了
There's nothing to worry about.
什么都不用担心
You're being decontaminated from the toxins which plague our world.
它会把你们身上沾染的 我们世界的毒素清洗掉
Please remove your clothes and place them in the incineration hatch.
请把你们的衣服脱了 然后丢进焚化炉
Please step forward.
上前一步
Place your feet on the mark.
站在标记上
You're clean.
搞定了
Please place your arm into the tube in the wall.
请把手放进墙上的孔道里
There's nothing to worry about, Tris.
不用有任何顾虑 翠丝
Please place your arm into the tube.
请把手放进孔道里
I've never felt so clean in my life.
这辈子都没这么干净过
That was the best weird shower I've ever had.
这是我洗过的最奇怪的澡了
A little cold thou.
有点儿冷 但是
Hey, yours is different.
你的纹身不一样
Why they are all different?
为什么都不一样
Hello, and welcome to the Bureau of Genetic Welfare.
你们好 欢迎各位光临基因福利局
In the early part of the 21st century, scientists first discovered a way to map
在21世纪上半时 科学家们首次发现并绘制了
then edit the human genome.
改变人类基因组的方法 你可以选择健康
You can choose to settle from "merely adequate" or you can choose "excellent".
你能选择保持自身的基因组 也能选择改善它们
A genetic solution puts you in control of your life.
基因解决方案让你可以掌控自己的生命
So, why just hope for a better future, when you can choose perfection?
为什么不期待一个更美好的未来 当你有机会选择完美时
Choose Perfexia.
请选择蒲飞霞
But, what started as an attempt to erase humanity's fault,
但是正如试图清楚人类缺陷一样
almost erased humanity itself.
人性也几乎被抹杀了
Genetic modification deepened the rifts between people.
基因改造加剧了人们之间的分歧
And as they got more entrenched, the world began to tear apart,
当矛盾越来越深 世界便开始四分五裂
until humanity cross a line, from which it could never return.
人类也因无法恢复原始基因而变得无可挽救
In the ashes of civilization,
在这片文明的废墟上
a small group of genetically unmodified individuals established the "BUREAU OF GENETIC WELFARE."
一小群基因未被改造的人建立了你们今天所在的这个基因福利局 “基因福利局”
here in Chicago's O'Hare Airport.
在这儿 芝加哥的奥黑尔机场
Our mission is to oversee a grand experiment
我们的任务是监控一项重要的实验
to purify the human genome.
其目的就是净化人类的基因组
That experiment is the city of Chicago.
而实验室就是芝加哥市
Your participation in the Bureau's work means you are now the guardians of the future.
你们参与到了基因局的工作 就意味着成为了人类未来的守护者
Your destiny begins today.
你们的使命从今天开始
Now. Please follow me.
现在请跟我来
What's an airport?
机场是什么鬼
Life in the Bureau can be demanding.
在这儿生活限制很多
The work is worth every sacrifice.
但是我们的值得为此付出
We don't have all the resources we would like of course,
基因局并不是要什么就有什么
but I think you'll find your accommodations more than adequate
但足以满足你们的基本生活
- Whoa. - Wow.
哇
They're in person, here.
他们是真人啊
- Who are they? - We bring them in from the Fringe.
他们是谁  从边界带回来的
Get them healthy. Give them a second chance.
等他们治好了 就能活下去了
- Hi, Four. - Hi, Four.
老四
Hi, Four.
Now they know who we are.
他们怎么知道我们的
The experiment is the entire focus of the Bureau.
实验室是整个基因局的焦点
Our Surveillance Technology is centuries ahead of anything you know in Chicago.
我们的监控技术领先你们芝加哥几个世纪
They grown up watching you.
他们看着你们长大
Nothing creepy about that.
你可吓着我们了
You have to forgive everyone for staring, but...
请原谅所有人都盯着你们看  但..
your arrival is the most exciting event some of us have ever known.
你们的到来对我们来说是件大事
Welcome to your new home.
欢迎来到新家
Where's Four? Did you hurt him?
老四在哪里 伤着他了吗
I told you I wanted them unharmed.
我说过我要他们几个毫发无损
He went with them. Willing.
跟他们走了 是自愿的
- But he's alive. - Did you hear what I'm saying?
他还活着吗 你没听懂吗
He betrayed you.
他背叛了你
No...
不
- It's just love. - He's your son.
都是因为爱情  他是你儿子
He should be loyal. I'm loyal!
他应该忠诚  像我这样
Yes, you are!
没错 你很忠诚
So, rest up. I need you ready to fight.
去休息吧 我要你做好战斗准备
What do you think?
想什么呢
I think they've been studying us for 200 years and we need to catch up.
他们研究了我们200年 我们得迎头赶上
We're going to give it a chance, right?
我们得抓住机会对吗
Yep, of course we are.
没错 完全正确
I wish we were alone.
真想单约你
Excuse me. The Director's ready to see you.
打扰一下 我们头儿说要见你
No, I'm sorry. I mean Tris, alone.
不 对不起 我说的是翠丝
We can't go together?
不能一起去吗
Since you were the one who opened the box which invited you here.
因为你是那个打开盒子的人
The Director would like to thank your personal.
所以我们头儿想要亲自感谢你
I'll see you later.
一会儿见
- Clothes. - Thanks.
衣服 谢谢
This way.
这边请
Go ahead. Put your wrist under the scanner.
来吧 手腕放在扫描仪上
Access granted.
允许 进入
Pure.
纯净
I just never imagined the world to be this big.
我从没想过还有次芝加哥大的地方
Chicago is just one of 50 major cities that used to exist
在北美 芝加哥只是过去50个大城市中的一个
on this continent along.
除此之外
Beyond that is, oceans and more land than you can imagine.
还有一望无际的还有和广阔的大陆
But it's all like this now?
现在都变样了
Yeah.
对
All except for Providence.
除了普罗维登斯
Which is why what we're doing here is so important, Tris.
所以我们在这儿做的事非常重要 翠丝
Hello.
你好
- You must be director. - Oh, please call me David.
你一定是头儿了   拜托 叫我大卫
It is a pleasure to finally meet you.
很高兴我终于见到你了
You must have so many questions.
你一定有很多疑问
I'm a bit overwhelmed. I'm still processing it and all.
我有点儿不知所措 我还在试着理解
Oh. Tris, I know you.
翠丝  我了解你
I watched you being born.
你一出生我就在观察你
I saw the love that your mother and father had for you.
我看到了你父母对你的爱
I watched a little girl have a happy childhood and grow into a courageous young woman
看到了一个拥有幸福童年的小姑娘是如何成长为一名
capable of making choices.
勇敢而果断的女孩
Dauntless. Defying Jeanine.
如入无畏派 推翻珍宁
Saving Chicago.
拯救芝加哥
To your people, you are a divergent.
对人民你是分歧者
To the Council, you're a freak.
对委员会 你是怪胎
To me, you are a a miracle.
对我 你就是个奇迹
David. are you-are you aware what's happening in Chicago right now?
大卫 你注意到芝加哥现在发生的事了吗
Of Course. Yes.
注意到了 当然
The people at Erudite really made a mess of things,
博学派的人真是够可以的
but I don't want your to worry about that.
但我不想你为这些担心
Restoring order in Chicago is as important to me as it is to you.
恢复芝加哥的秩序对你和我都很重要
It's the only way to save the "damaged".
这是拯救缺陷者的唯一办法
What is the "damaged".
什么是缺陷者
The genetic alterations had disastrous consequences.
基因改造产生了严重的后果
Too brave and you're cruel. Too peaceful and you're passive.
太勇敢会变得残忍 太平和会变得懦弱
Too smart, and you'll lose compassion, like your brother.
太聪明会变得冷酷 就像你哥哥
- Caleb's "damaged"? - Yes.
凯莱布是缺陷者吗  没错
For nearly 200 years,
近200年来
the greatest scientific minds have live here to test a theory.
顶尖的科学家们在这儿验证一个理论
If we can rescue genetically damaged people
如果我们能把边界地带
from the toxic environment in the Fringe.
有毒环境中的基因缺陷者
and put them in a safe place like Chicago,
放在像芝加哥这样安全的城市里
then perhaps over time, man's genetic material would heal itself.
也许久而久之 人们的基因就能治愈自己
Return to its original form.
这样就可以回到原来的样子了
And I'm one of those people?
我就是其中的一个
You're the only one.
你是唯一的一个
That doesn't- That doesn't make any sense
你这么说没道理 我是说
Four is divergent. There's lot of divergences.
老四也是分歧者 还有很多分歧者
Not divergent, Tris. Pure.
不是分歧者  翠丝  是纯净者
You're genetically "pure". The rest are still "damaged".
你是基因纯净者  其他人都是缺陷者
- Four? - Damaged.
老四呢  缺陷者
Not as much as Caleb, but "damaged".
不像凯莱布那么严重  但也是缺陷者
If we can understand what made you,
如果我们能知道是什么治愈了你
maybe we can use that knowledge to help the "damaged".
也许我们就能帮助其他的缺陷者了
What does this have to do with Chicago?
但这跟芝加哥有什么关系
I answer to the Council.
我会向委员会汇报
They're the ones who ultimately determine our fate.
他们是最终决定我们命运的人
Yours and mine.
你们的和我的
I'm going to bring you with me to Providence to meet them.
我准备带你去见他们
When they see that it's possible, that you were possible,
当他们看见这是有可能的 你就是那个可能性
it will change everything.
一切都会改变
I understand it's hard to take my word for it.
我明白我的话很难的到信任
But, if you don't believe me, believe your mother.
但是若果你不相信我 就相信你母亲
My mother?
我母亲
Your mother, Natalie, wasn't born in Chicago.
你母亲纳塔莉不是出生在芝加哥
She was born in the Fringe and rescued by the Bureau.
她出生在边界地带 然后被基因局救了
No, that's impossible.
不 这根本不可能
See for yourself.
眼见为实
What are these?
这是什么
They're your mother's memory tabs.
这是你目前的记忆卡
With them, you can watch the world through her eyes.
有了这些你就能通过她的眼睛去看世界
What do I do?
我该怎么做
Place one on each temple.
在太阳穴上各放一枚
Natalie, come on!
纳塔莉 快点儿
I'm not Natalie.
我不是纳塔莉
We need to hide! Come on!
我们得藏起来  快点儿
They're coming! Run!
他们来了 快跑
The Fringers!
是边界掠夺者
Run!
快跑
The Fringers!
是边界掠夺者
I'm not Natalie.
我不是纳塔莉
Natalie, no!
纳塔莉 不
No!
不
Bureau soldiers!
基因局的士兵
Left! Flank left!
左边  左翼包抄
Keep right! Keep right! Keep right!
打右边
We're taking you to the Bureau. You're safe.
我们带你到基因局  你安全了
You don't have to be afraid anymore.
不用再担惊受怕了
- How many more did you save today? - Not enough.
今天又救了多少个孩子  不够多
We never get enough.
永远都不够多
Chicago has got to work, David. It's the only hope for us.
芝加哥必须发挥作用 大卫  这是我们唯一的希望
From the ashes of civilization, a small group of genetically unmodified individuals
在这片文明的废墟上  一小群基因违背改造的人
established the Bureau of Genetic Welfare, here at Chicago's O'Hare airport.
建立了你们今天所在的这个基因福利局 在这儿 芝加哥的奥黑尔机场
You're safe.
你安全了
a grand experiment, to purify the human genome.
起目的就是净化人类的基因组
You're safe now.
你现在安全了
Your destiny begins today.
你们的使命 从今天开始
Tris.
翠丝
In a moment of need, your mother did something
在危机关头 你母亲做了一件从
that no one had done before.
没有人做过的事
She volunteered to leave the safety of the Bureau
她自愿离开安全的基因局
to enter the experiment herself.
让自己加入到实验中
She did this because she knew the "damaged" were worth saving.
她做这些是因为她知道应该拯救缺陷者
She believed in the experiment so much she was willing to be a part of it.
她非常相信实验所以她自愿加入到实验中
If I can show the Council your miracle can be replicated,
如果我让委员会看到这个奇迹可以被复制
then her life's work is complete.
那么她一生的工作就圆满了
The Council will be force to look at any human being,
委员会不得不公平对待每个生命
No matter where they were born, is worthy of life.
不管他们来自哪里，都有权利生存
Help me. You saved a city.
帮帮我 你救了一座城市
Help me save the world.
帮我拯救这个世界
It was amazing.
太不可思议了
It was like I was her and seeing it all through her eyes.
好像我变成了她，并通过她的眼睛看到了一切
I still can't believe my mom is from this place.
我还是不能相信我妈妈来自这儿
Well, I can see why she left.
我理解你妈妈为什么要离开了
Do you trust him? David.
你相信他吗，大卫？
I trust her.
我相信我妈妈
Yeah.
是的
Access denied.
禁止进入
Tris.
翠斯
Access granted.
允许进入
Here you are. You ready?
你来了，你准备好了吗？
Say hi to David for me.
替我问候大卫
Tobias Eaton.
托比亚斯·伊顿
You've been assigned to me.
你分配到我的部门了
I am Nita. Let's go.
我是尼塔 ，我们走
Why isn't everyone allowed upstairs?
为什么不是所有人都能上来
That would be one of the Council's many rules.
这是委员会重多规定中的一条
Certainly not mine.
我也没办法
The Separation, I don't like it.
这是隔离 我不喜欢
I agree, and in time, that won't be necessary.
我同意你的看法 这些到最后都是多余的
第一时间更新中文字幕网
-= 字 幕 谷 论 坛 =-
But Tris, I don't know who told you that being different is a bad thing.
但是翠斯，我不知道是谁告诉你与众不同是件坏事
Because I know it wasn't your mother.
因为我知道不是你母亲
Now I know I can replicate this. All I need is time.
我知道能复制你的基因图谱，只是时间问题
Look, Regina, let's talk. You seem like a nice lady, but...
听着 雷吉纳 我们得谈谈，你看上去像个好人
I'm really not a desk job kind of guy.
但我真的不适合坐办公室工作
I get claustrophobic.
我有幽闭恐惧症
I need to be where the action is.
我得待在开放的地方
The job of Surveillance is to keep tabs
监视工作就要密切关注
on the developing situation in Chicago.
芝加哥日益动荡的局势
This is where the action is.
这工作绝对放得开
Hayes, this will be your pod. Prior, you're next door.
海斯 这是你的监控室 普勒尔 你在隔壁的那间
Resistance is growing. Evelyn is beginning to respond.
抵抗日益激烈 伊芙琳是比会有所行动
Watch what's happening, file a report.
密切监视 然后提交报告
Wait. What... Hold on. I just escaped from Chicago.
等等 天哪 我刚从芝加哥逃出来
Now you're saying, I got to sit here and watch it
现在你却要我后半辈子坐在这，监视它
for the rest of my life? With Caleb?
和它一起？
Perhaps you prefer to be banished to the Fringe?
也许你更愿意被驱逐到边界地带
Ah. This Surveillance technology is incredible.
这儿的监控技术太不可思议了
- Whoever created it, is a genius. - Well, thank you.
造它的人一定是个天才  -谢谢你
It was a labor of love.
能热爱你的工作
Ass kisser.
马屁精
Keep it up, Prior.
把那个捡起来 普勒尔
And you, get to it.
还有你 开始工作
首发超清电影网
-= 字幕谷 www.zimugu.com =-
It's an awful lot of firepower.
火力够充足的
The Fringe is full of dangerous people.
边界地带危机四伏
Put this on.
穿上这个
- What are these? - Personal drones.
这些是什么？ -私人无人机
Expands your field of vision and provides 3D modeling and environments.
它能扩大视野，为你构建周围环境的3D模型
Just like old times in Dauntless, huh?
就像过去在无畏派一样，不是吗？
Except there is nothing old about any of this.
除了没有过时的东西以外
Here.
给你
Thanks.
谢谢
Activate the head gear.
激活头盔
The left hand activates the drones.
左手激活无人机
[SCANNING]
ID: FOUR
Does it do anything else?
还能做别的吗
Not much.
不太多
Use the drones to find the targets.
也就是用无人机找目标
It will take you a while to get the hang of it.
你需要花些时间才能熟悉它
Yeah.
是的
Okay.
好的
Identified.
目标确认
[SCANNING]
Target Identified.
目标已经确认
I think I got the hang of it.
我想我已经熟悉了
Can I ask you a question?
我能问你个问题？
- Yeah, of course. - If mother was born in the Fringe,
是的，当然 -如果我母亲出生在边界地带
then, how did she end up in Chicago.
那她是怎么到芝加哥的
I mean, you couldn't just sent her through the gate, right?
我是说你不可能把她送到了城门口吧？
No.
不是的
Now, the Council's always careful how they introduced any new element to the experiment.
委员会总是很谨慎的安置新人到实验室，他们需要中介人
Right. But, when they need to, they intervene.
中介人需要时就会介入
Yes.
是的
So, why aren't they intervening now?
那为什么现在还不介入呢？
They will. We just have to make our case.
他们会的 只要我们能说服他们
- Can I still count on you to help me? - Yes.
我能相信你会帮助我妈？ 当然
Can I count on you?
我能相信你妈？
Jeanine never had a chance against you.
珍妮是绝对没有机会打倒你的
The sooner we get finished, the sooner we leave for Providence.
我们越快做好准备，就能越早去普罗维斯登
The Allegiant. That's what you're calling yourselves.
忠诚者，你们这么称呼自己
Amity just doesn't seem appropriate anymore.
友好派这个称呼已经不再适合了
So, what exactly are you allegiant to? The faction system?
那么你们到底忠诚于什么？派别体系？
The factions kept Chicago peaceful for a long time.
派系在很长时间里维持了芝加哥的和平
Well, I wouldn't know about that because I was forced out of my faction.
我并不了解这个，因为我被迫离开了派系
I gave up my life, my child, everything.
我放弃了我的生活，我的孩子，所有
I understand your anger, Evelyn, I do.
我理解你的愤怒 伊芙琳 真的
- But the way forward... - The way forward has already began.
但是未来的路 -未来的路已经铺好了
I know I said I'd be alone, but...
我说过我会一个人来
I'm not Candor and I'm not Amity.
但我不是诚实派也不是友好派
So I will lie and I will fight if I have to.
所以我撒了谎 如果有必要的话我还会战斗
You see these scars? I wasn't born Amity.
看见这些伤疤了吗？我不是出生在友好派
And I can assure you I'm not afraid to fight for what I believe in.
我能向你保证 我并不害怕为信念而战
It seems like we're 2 peas in a pot.
看来我们是同一类人
But it doesn't have to be this way.
但并不一定非要这种方式
We can come to some sort of agreement.
我们可以好好商量
- Get back! - Get down!
退后 ！-趴下
- Get out of here! - Let's go.
离开这 -我们走
- Go! - Go.
快-快
Alright, Caleb.
听着 凯莱布
Keep me posted if anything changes, alright?
万一情况有变通知我好吗？
- Hi. - Hey.
你好-你也是
Caleb said that some of the Dauntless are lining with Johanna.
凯莱布说无畏派的一些人站到了约翰娜这边
But the rest of Candor are still solid with Evelyn.
但剩下的诚实派还和伊芙琳一个阵营
Things are  finally out of control.
局势就快失去控制了
Did David say anything about what he can do?
大卫说过他能做什么吗？
Yeah, once we talk to the Council, then the Bureau can step in.
我们跟委员会谈完 基因局会介入
So, it all hinges on the mysterious Council, does it?
所以这全靠神秘的委员会了 对吧？
- What if they say no? - David is confident that they won't.
他们不同意怎么办？ -大卫有信心说服他们
David, right.
大卫，好吧
You know, I found out why I can't go upstairs.
你知道，我搞清楚自己为什么不能上去了
I'm "damaged", and you're "pure".
我是缺陷者 你是纯净者
I know.
我知道
You know. When were you going to tell me?
你知道 你打算什么时候告诉我？
I don't know. I...
我不知道 我……
- I guess I didn't think that it matter. - Why doesn't it matter?
但我觉得这并不重要-为什么不重要？
Because it doesn't make a difference if you're "pure" or  you're "damaged".
因为不管是纯净者还是缺陷者都没什么区别
You're still the same person to me.
对我来说你就是你
Look. I know that it's not perfect, by any means, but...
听着 我知道无论如何它都不完美
The Bureau saved my mother from the Fringe. I wouldn't be here without her.
但基因局从边界地带救出了我妈妈，没有他们我也不会再这儿
What do you actually know about what they do in the Fringe?
我们真的了解他们在哪儿做过什么吗？
You know what they tell you.
你只是听他们说的
- Yeah, but... - I'm sorry.
是的 但是 -打扰下
He needs you upstairs.
他要你去楼上
他请你去楼上
Those people are nice, weird, but nice.
那些人恨友好，虽然奇怪 但很友好
Yeah. They're definitely weird, that's for sure.
是啊 他们的确很奇怪
You better get used to it.
你已经习惯了
- Really? - Yeah.
是吗？ -没错
Next time you go to the Fringe, I want in.
下次去边界地带带上我，我想加入
You're not ready.
你还没准备好
I'm going.
我准备好了
Tris.
翠斯
I'm more than aware that the separation
我注意到分离对于你和老四来说很困难
has been difficult for you and Four, but...
I've watched you both enough to know that
但我已经观察你们很久了
I think the two of you are going to work it out.
我想你们该解决下彼此之间的矛盾
We're fine.
我们很好
Everything's fine.
一直都很好
Good. Let's get to work.
好吧，我们去工作
Here we go! Fall in people!
我们走 大家集合
The weather's clear, we're green for a run!
天气晴朗 执行逮捕行动
- You, let's go, let's go! - Come on, come on.
你们行动快点 我们走
- Move! Let's go! - Get ready to go!
我们走
Let's go!
Alright, here's the deal. Listen up!
好了 情况是这样的 听好了
This may be a Humanitarian mission,
这是一个人道主义任务
but the dwindle assembly is very dangerous.
但是林尔代据点非常危险
- Everybody clear? - Yes!
大家都听清楚了吗   -清楚
- So, what's the life span out here? - 25 to 30 years.
外面的人平均能活多久？  -25到30岁
But if we get people early, they can live up to 50 or 60 in the Bureau.
如果小时候就被救了，在基因局能活到50-60岁
Dauntless, if it's up to me, you would not be out here.
无畏派 如果是我就不会让你们来这儿
I know you think it was tough in Chicago, but this is the Fringe.
我知道你们觉得芝加哥很危险
- Understood? - Yes.
听懂了吗？在这里更加危险  -是的
The mission is to save as many kids as possible.
我们的任务是尽可能的救更多的孩子
They grow up in hellish conditions.
避免他们在恶劣的环境中长大
But, you have your weapons handy, you stick to protocol.
虽然你们手上有武器，但不要轻易使用
I don't want to lose any one.
我不想有任何伤亡
Get out your weapons.
带上你们的武器
Come on, let's go!
来吧，进攻
Go! Go! Go. We got to move!
快  我们得行动了
Drones!
启动无人机
Go!
走
Help!
帮帮我
Stop. Stop, stop. Hey, hey, hey. It's okay.
停下来 好了 没事了 出去
I want my dad. Please!
放我下来 求你了
No! No! Dad!
不  不 不 爸爸
Everything will be fine. Let's go. Let's go.
没事了  跟着我
Come on!
加油
Run!
跑
Searching Target.
目标搜索中
This way. This way.
这边跑
Target identified.
目标已确认
Go!
快
- Stop! - Just stay away from us!
站在  离我们远点儿
- Calm down. We're here to help. - We don't need your help.
冷静点  我们是来帮你们的  -我们不需要你的帮助
- I just want to talk to you. - I'm not going to lose my family!
我们想跟你谈谈  -我不想失去家人
Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa. Stop!
站住 不要
-  Let go! Get away! - Get off him!
放开他  走开  别碰他
Get off him! Don't touch my boy!
别碰他  别碰我儿子
What did you do?
你做了什么？
Come on. It's okay. It's alright.
来吧 没事了
- I want to see my dad. - I know, I know.
我想见我爸爸 - 我知道
Four, let's go! We got to move!
老四   快走   我们撤
It's alright. It's okay.
没事的  没事了
Go! We got to go, we got to go.
我们走 快点儿
It's okay. Come on. Come on.
没事了 跟我走
- Romit! - Don't.
罗米特  -让开
What the hell is going on here?
究竟发生了什么事
Just do you job, Dauntless.
做好你自己的事  无畏派
Let's go! Move!
我们走 快
Let's go!
我们走
One man, two children. Get them on the plane, go!
一个男人 2个小孩 抓住他们上飞机 ，快
Get back here!
回来
No!
不
I said, shut up. All of you.
闭嘴 你们都
- Hey. - You, stop!
你 站住
It's called a soap, you should try it.
这是香皂 你应该用用
What's up, Stiff? You lost?
怎么了 僵尸人  迷路了？
I wanted to see Four.
我找老四
David and I are leaving for Providence.
大卫和我准备去普罗维凳斯
On a first name bases with the director, huh?
和关系亲密的头儿一起吗
- You work fast. - Peter, can you leave her alone.
进展的挺快啊  皮特 别烦她了
I don't need you to defend me.
我不需要你帮我
Attention!
立正
Get us ready for Providence. I want my ship within an hour.
做好去普罗维登斯的准备
- Yes, sir. - Follow me.
是的 长官  -跟上我
David, hey.
大卫，嘿
I was wondering if I can talk to you about my job.
我在想是否我能和你谈谈我的工作
You know, I'm not really a typist and...
你知道 我真的不适合坐办公室
Or if you are busy today, I get it.
如果你很忙  我能理解
Totally fine, we'll talk tomorrow.
没事儿 我们明天再聊也行
Good idea.
好主意
Thank you.
谢谢
I need to talk to you.
我要跟你谈谈
What is this, Nita?
这是干嘛 塔尼
Vaccinations.
打疫苗
What do you mean, vaccinations? We weren't given vaccinations.
什么  打疫苗？我们几个都没打疫苗
Four.
老四
Look at this.
看看这个
Hey. What's your name?
嘿 你叫什么名字
My name?
我的名字？
Hey.
嘿
- I'm sorry about your dad. - My dad?
你爸爸的事我很抱歉  -我爸爸？
- Alright, I'll see you back at base. - Yep.
好了  基因局总部见 -好的
This is not a humanitarian mission.
这不是人道主义任务
We're not saving kids, we're stealing them.
我们不是在救孩子 我们在绑架他们
This is what we do. Now you know.
这就是我们做的工作 现在你知道了
David takes them out from here,
大卫从这儿把他们带走
wipes their memories with the gas, and raises them in the Bureau.
用记忆血清抹除他们的记忆，让他们在基因局长大
If you take away what they know, then you take away who they are.
如果抹除了他们的记忆，也就抹掉了他们的身份
Yeah. I think that's the point.
没错 这就是目的
They were all unarmed.
他们都没有武器
I won't surrender to this.
我不会因此投降的
Round up anyone who's left.
看看还有没有活着的
We take the fight to Evelyn.
我们要跟伊芙琳开战
Yeah. I'm loading up.
好 我去装车
Let's go.
我们走
Move it.
移开这个
Today we take Evelyn down!
今天我们要打倒伊芙琳
Whatever it takes!
不惜一切代价
This is all real time.
这是现场直播
I mean, this Surveillance Technology they have in place is extraordinary.
我们在这儿的监控技术简直了得
Caleb, can you get out of your head for a second?
凯莱布 能别想自己的事儿吗？
This is our home.
那儿是我们的家
There's going to be a war.
那儿就要开战了
Where are you going?
你要去哪儿？
I'm going to do something about it.
得为芝加哥做点什么
Four, what are you trying to do?
老四  你这是要去干什么
Getting Tris. We're leaving.
我去找翠斯 我们得离开
You can't go up there.
你不能上去
- What do you think you are doing? - Four!
你知道自己在干什么吗?  -老四
- You cannot be in here. - Four.
你不能在这儿  -老四
- It's not going to work. - Pure.
这么做没用的    纯净
Central elevator has been compromised.
中央电梯被入侵了
- Hey. - We're leaving.
嘿  -我们得离开这儿
- What? - Right now.
什么？ -马上
What? I can't.
什么？我不能走
You don't understand yet, but these people have been lying to you.
听着 你还不了解情况 这些人在骗你
Lying? What are you talking about?
骗局？你在说什么？
Look, whatever they told you. They've been...
听着 不管他们说什么 其实他们……
Put the guns down.
放下武器
He's been stealing children from their families.
这个大卫他一直都在抢别人的孩子
We're giving them a better life.
我们给了他们更好的生活
- By killing their parents? - It was an unfortunate accident. Sir.
就因此杀了他们父母？  -那只是个意外 长官
One terrible accident doesn't mean that it was the wrong thing to do.
一个可怕的意外不代表这么做是错的
Tris, This is not the place that we thought it was suppose to be.
翠斯 这个地方跟我们想的不一样
If you have enough to save one person,
如果你有能力去救一个人
and your choice was between a healthy child or a sick old man,
你选择救健康的孩子 还是救生病的老人
- who would you choose? - I wouldn't choose!
你选谁 我不会选择
Good, now they're both dead.
好吧  那他们都会死
We have to go.
我们得走了
Tris. We're going back to Chicago, we shouldn't ever have left.
翠斯 我们得回芝加哥去  我们从没离开过
- No, we have to wait. - Yeah, we've been waiting.
不 我们得再等等 -是的  我们一直在等待
Okay, David is not the person that you think he is.
大卫根本就不是你想的那种人
Four, you know nothing about David.
老四 你不了解大卫
You've no idea what we've been working up here.
你不了解我们都在这儿忙什么
What have you been working on?
你们忙些什么？
Do you have any idea what is going on out there?
你知道芝加哥现在发生什么了吗？
Yes, of course I do.
知道 我当然知道
Why do you think we're going to meet with the Council?
这就是我们为什么要去见委员会的人？
Tris.
翠斯
I want you to listen to me.
我求你认真听我说 翠斯
Tris.
翠斯
You're coming with me.
跟我回去
I have to go.
我得走了
You're making a mistake.
你犯了一个错误
You ready?
你准备好了？
Yeah.
是的
Autopilot engage.
启动自动驾驶仪
You want to go back to Chicago, I'll take you.
你想回芝加哥 我载你
No, thanks.
不 谢谢
You want to walk cross the Fringe, I don't think so.
就这么走着穿越边界地带
There's no rule saying you can't go home, Four.
没有规定说你不能走 老四
Come on.
跟我来
- Yeah. - I'll go with you.
好吧  -我跟你们去
All set.
准备就绪
Take us to Chicago.
带我们去芝加哥
Look, I understand how you're feeling. But...
听着  我能理解你的感受
What you're about to do has ramifications for people all over the world.
但是你现在要做的事对全世界而言将产生巨大的影响
If Four doesn't see that, it's not your fault.
如果老四不理解 也不要往心里去
David never wanted you to see what you saw, out on the Fringe.
大卫根本不想让你看到边界地带的事
He keeps tight control. Nothing happens without his approval.
他一直严格控制 他没允许我们这么做
And his ship, is the only one that can fly through the camo wall.
他的飞船是唯一可以穿越伪装墙的
Why are you telling me this?
为什么告诉我这些
We are not taking you to Chicago.
我们不会送你去芝加哥
Hold on!
抓紧
Welcome to Providence.
欢迎来到普罗维斯登
I can see why they don't want to share it.
明白他们为什么不愿意分享了
Some day, the whole world is going to look this beautiful.
有一天全世界都会像这儿一样美
So, as you can see, there are multiple
如诸位所知的，有多种基因标记可以支撑这个结论
genetic markers supporting this conclusion.
Standard personality test. Behavioral evaluations. Stimulus response.
标准性格测试 行为评估 刺激反应
She's passed them all with flying colors.
她轻易的通过了所有的测试
It all sounds great assuming it's the truth.
如果这是真的 听起来确实不错
Phillip.
菲利普
David has lied to us before, haven't you, David?
大卫以前骗过我们 不是吗 大卫？
I like to hear from the girl.
让这个女孩说说
Well, I don't know why she can't tell you anything I'm not.
要知道 她可不会为了我而撒谎
Indulge us, David.
帮个忙 大卫
This must all come as quite a shock to you, Miss Prior,
发现自己是分歧者（纯洁者）对你来说一定很吃惊吧 普勒尔小姐
finding out that you are pure
Um.
嗯
Pure. I'm not even sure what's that suppose to mean.
纯洁者 我甚至都不知道是什么
But yes, it is shocking to me.
没错 我很吃惊
Shocking that the more I learn about the past, the more I feel like...
我对过去了解更多就越感到
you're all making the same mistakes over and over again.
你们好像一直在犯同一个错误
- Tris, this is not the way. - Let her speak, David.
翠斯 别这么说 -让她继续 大卫
What mistakes, Tris?
什么错误 翠斯？
The human beings cannot be categorized in this way.
人类不能用这种方法进行分类
It doesn't work.
这是没用的
Maybe it's time to start embracing everyone instead of dividing them into groups.
也许是时候接受所有人了，而不是把他们分在不同的群体里
Regardless whether they are 'pure' or they are 'damaged'.
无论他们是纯洁者还是缺陷者
- That isn't what we're here to discuss. - Well, it should be.
这不是我们要讨论的问题  -是的
Look, I know that all of this is just an experiment to you,
听着 我知道一切对你们来说是一项实验
but these people in Chicago are real.
但对芝加哥的人民来说缺是真实的
And they're in a war right now because of divisions that you created,
你们创建的派系导致他们现在仍生活在战乱里
and you are doing nothing to help them.
你们却坐视不管
David has control over the administration of Chicago.
你要知道大卫才是掌握芝加哥管理权的人
He's only here to extend his funding.
他来这儿只是为了增加他的经费
Which, we would be happy to do,
我们乐于做某些事
but if things are as bad as she says, David.
但如果真像她说的那么差劲 大卫
Shouldn't you get your house in order first?
你难道不应该先回家呆着吗？
You said that you couldn't do anything.
你跟我说过你无能为力
I am doing something. I'm bring back the factions.
我在行动了  我在重建派别制度
What? Why?
什么？为什么？
I hope the Allegiant will take care of the problem for me.
我希望忠诚者能为我解决这个问题
The factions work, Tris.
派系是有用的 翠斯
They keep the peace, they created you.
它们维护了和平 成就了你
I never should have trusted you.
我真不应该相信你
You want change with no sacrifice, you want peace with no struggle.
你不想牺牲就革命，你想不斗争就迎来和平
The world doesn't work like that.
这个世界不是这样的
You okay?
你还好吗？
I'll be fine.
我没事
I hope the Bureau isn't far.
快到基因局了
I need to get to Chicago, and tell Evelyn
我想回芝加哥 告诉伊芙琳她犯的错比约翰娜更严重
she's got a lot bigger problem than Johanna.
You'll need this, to get through the camo wall.
你需要这个才能穿越伪装墙
We need your help, Tobias.
我们需要你的帮助 托比亚斯
You don't know what he's capable of.
你不了解大卫的真面目
What about Tris?
翠斯怎么样了
As long as she stays in the Bureau, she's safe.
只要呆在基因局 她就是安全的
She's too valuable to him.
她对大卫来说很重要
I'll need a head start.
我要先考虑下
When David asks,
如果大卫闻起来
I want you to tell him that I left you behind.
你就跟他说我背叛了你们
Okay?
好吗？
- Why? - Because Tris will know you're lying.
为什么？ -因为翠斯会知道你在说谎
SCANNING
PURE @ MATTHEW.B ACCESS GRANTED
纯净派 马修·B 允许通行
There was an accident.
出了点事
There was turbulence, not more than any other storm, but...
遇到一股气流，虽然没有风暴厉害，也许有闪电
The lightning, maybe.
也许有闪电
- We just went down. - Where's Four?
接着飞机就坠毁了 老四呢？
I don't know.
我不知道
I passed out, when I cam to, everyone was dead.
我失去意识了  当我醒来的时候所有人都死了
Four left me behind.
老四丢下了我
Okay, we search the settlement, search the Fringe.
好吧  找找那些据点
Make sure he's not there.
确定他在不在那儿
Don't worry. We'll find him, I promise.
别担心 我们会找到他的 我保证
Four would never leave anyone behind at the crash site.
老四是绝对不会出了意外后丢下任何人的
Yeah. He told me you would say that.
是的  他跟我说过你一定会这么说
Four is trying to make his way back to Chicago.
老四这会儿在回芝加哥的路上
- Peter. - Hello, David.
皮特 -你好，大卫
I didn't think that you knew my name.
我以为你不知道我的名字
I know all of the important people from Chicago.
我了解所有芝加哥来的重要人物
Really?
真的？
Well, if I'm so important,
那么 我是重要人物了
then why did you give me such a terrible job?
为什么你还让我干那么烂的活儿
We all have to make sacrifices.
我们都得做出一些牺牲
I don't see you making any.
你牺牲了？
Peter.
皮特
I need help with something in Chicago.
我需要芝加哥那边有人帮我
What's in it for me?
我有什么好处？
Well, if you do well, you can have any job you want.
如果完成不错 工作随便你挑
Except mine.
除了我的
Do you know where Peter is ?
知道皮特在哪儿吗？
Uh, he's not in his pod?
嗯 他不在监控室吗？
No.
没有
No, I don't know where he is.
那就不知道了
Is there something that I can help you with?
有什么需要帮忙的吗？
Can you find Four?
你能找到老四
You can't tell anyone.
你不能告诉别人
Okay, of course.
当然
Anything you need, Beatrice.
都听你的 碧翠斯
Come on, Four, where are you?
快点儿 老四  你在哪儿？
Evelyn. We found him outside the wall.
伊芙琳 我们在围墙外发现了他
Take it off.
把面罩拿下
Where's my son?
我儿子在哪儿？
I don't know.
我不知道
Edgar told me what's out there.
埃德告诉了我围墙外的情况
So you better start talking, or we'll be holding your trial now!
所以你最好说点什么，否则我会马上就审判你
No, you won't.
不  你不会的
Because I have something that you need.
因为我有你想要的东西
Really? And what's that?
真的？是什么？
The way to win your war.
赢得战争的胜利的方法
- Hey. - Hey.
嘿  - 嘿
Any news?
有消息？
No.
没有
I'm sorry.
对不起
Tris!
翠斯
- Did you find him? - Yes, I found Four.
你在找他？  -是的，我找到老四了
And there's something else you're going to want to see too.
你还是过来看看吧
Okay, go.
好的，来吧
Over there! That's him! We got him!
在那儿，就是他 发现他了
Four.
老四
Don't worry, he's fine. Just... keep watching.
别担心 他很好，只是……继续看
What is this place?
那是什么地方？
You're going to love it.
你会爱上它的
What is it?
这是什么
Try it out. You'll see.
试一下 就知道了
Just don't try it on anyone you like.
别用在你喜欢的人身上
I was wondering when you'll have the courage to face me.
我一直在想你什么时候才有勇气面对我
3 weeks you leave me here.
我在这儿已经三个星期了
I run a faction!
我管理着一个派系
I protected our son from Jeanine's thugs.
我保护我们的儿子不受珍妮的迫害
Protected him. Is that what you call it?
你保护他  这就叫保护？
Beating your own child.
暴打你自己的孩子
It made him who he is.
这才成就了今天的他
Make sure he gets a good dose.
注意控制下剂量
Tobias, I was trying to make you to be better.
托比亚斯 我这么做只想让你变得更好
I'm-I'm sorry, but...
对不起 但是……
Who you are?
可是你是谁？
Just imagine if you release this on the Allegiant.
想象一下把这个用在忠诚者身上
Not even Johanna will remember a time that you weren't in charge.
甚至连约翰娜都不会记得你曾经不是这里的领导者
Who exactly told you about this?
这个东西是谁给你的
You have a very powerful friend on the outside,
你在墙外面有个很厉害的朋友
if you choose to engage instead of prepare.
只要你选择合作而不是反抗
- Does this friend have a name? - David.
这位朋友叫什么名字？ -大卫
David?
大卫？
You can tell my friend I'm not going to use that thing unless it's the last resort.
你可以告诉我这位的朋友，不到最后一刻我是不会用这个东西的
Why would David support Evelyn?
大卫为什么要支持伊芙琳？
It doesn't make any sense.
完全没道理
Are you okay? I was worried about you.
你还好吗？我很担心你
Evelyn, you need to make peace with the Allegiant.
伊芙琳 你跟忠诚者讲和
No, Johanna made her choice. I never wanted this war.
不 约翰娜已经做出了选择。我从没想过发动战争
But I will end it, I promise you.
我会结束它的。我保证
You have no idea what you are up against.
你都不知道你的敌人是谁
- Johanna is not the issue. - Look.
约翰娜不是问题的关键 -听着
I know you're angry at me and I understand that.
我知道你还在生我的气
I'm just... I never meant...
我只是……我从没想到……
This is so hard for me too.
现在对我来说也很艰难
I don't want to have to keep you in here.
我心里也不想把你关在这儿
Then, let me out.
那么 放我出去
I can't, I have responsibilities.
我做不到 因为这是我的责任
One day, you'll understand that, but right now I need you to stay here.
总有一天你会理解我的，但是你现在必须待在这儿
I'm going to finish this. One way or another.
我会结束一切的，无论发生什么
How are you going to finish this?
你打算怎么结束这一切？
Hey, don't worry. You won't have to be here for long.
别担心 你不会待太久的
What-What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Well, Evelyn is deciding now,
伊芙琳还在拿主意
If she use the memory serum, Chicago might forget it's own name.
如果她使用记忆血清，所有人都会忘了自己是谁
We have to go.
我们得走了
Get Christina and meet me outside.
脚上克里斯蒂娜 在外面碰头
Where are we going?
我们要去哪儿？
Home.
回家
Access granted.
允许进入
How's it going in Chicago?
芝加哥那边怎么样了？
Making sure it's safe from Evelyn and the factionless?
确定伊芙琳她们没有危险的举动？
Tris.
翠斯
You need to forget about Chicago.
你要忘掉芝加哥
You know, it's really funny, David.
你知道，你真是可笑 大卫
You've been watching me for years and you don't know anything about me.
你观察我这么多年却一点都不了解我
You're wiping the memories of everyone in Chicago, aren't you?
你打算清楚芝加哥城里所有人的记忆
- Alright. Uh... - You were never supporting the Allegiant.
没错 -你根本就不支持忠诚者
These people treated you terribly, they killed your parents.
别忘了这些人背叛了你，他们杀了你的父母
- Four is there! - Oh, Four.
老四在那里 -哦 老四
Yes. Yes. Four is there.
是的  老四在那儿
But he's "damaged", just like the rest of them.
但是他是缺陷者，跟其他人是一样的
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
I'm taking your ship and I'm not come back.
坐你的飞船离开  不会再回来了
You can't fly.
你不会开
Watch me.
看好了
Autopilot engage.
启动自动驾驶仪
Tris Prior is stealing my craft, bring her back.
翠斯·普勒尔偷走了我的飞船，抓她回来
Hurry.
快
- Cristina, these are for you and Tris. - How did you know we were leaving?
克里斯蒂娜，这是给你和翠斯的 -你怎么知道我们要走？
You're not the only ones who hate David.
不是只有你一个人恨大卫
- Hey, come on! - Thank you.
嘿，快点儿 -谢谢你
- Hold it! - Get in, get in.
接住！进来
Hands to yourself or I'll throw you out.
把你的手拿开  不然把你扔出去
Let's go rescue Four.
我们去救老四
Looks like 3 ships are following us.
有三艘飞船跟踪我们
- Plasma craft engaged. - Surround her.
包围住 -使他迫降
Give her a nudge towards the ground. The autopilot will bring her down safely.
自动驾驶仪能让飞船安全着陆
What are they trying to do?
他们想干什么？
They're trying to bring us in for a landing!
他们想让我们迫降
I'm going manual!
我换手操作
- Pull up! Pull up! - I'm trying!
拉起来 -我在努力
I'm trying!
我在努力
Altitude
注意高度
I got it.
成功了
Your order, sir?
请下令 长官
Shoot her down.
把她的飞船击落
Before she reaches the camo wall. You can't follow her through.
在她到达伪装墙之前
We're dead.
我们死定了
We're gonna die! We're gonna die!
我们死定了……
Hold on.
抓稳了
We're getting close!
我们快到了
- Ho! - Whoa!
呼……
There has to be a way to shut off the gas.
一定可以阻止记忆血清的扩散
Look at the ventilation system, it's all over the city.
看看遍布城市的通风系统
Down there.
看那儿
Johanna.
约翰娜
We got here just in time.
我们正来的是时候
It's time, Evelyn.
是时候了，伊芙琳
You said, the gas was a last resort.
你说过记忆血清是你的最后一招
Well?
是吗？
How do think your trial is going to end?
你认为对你的审判会是什么结果？
Let me know the second the serum is released.
血清一旦释放就立刻通知我
You got it. Good luck.
明吧 祝你好运
Thank you.
谢谢
How do these drones work?
这无人机怎么用？
Turn your headgear on.
戴上头盔
- And? - Watch and learn.
然后？ -看着学
Stop right there and drop your weapons!
站住 放下武器
Hey, hey! Whoa! Hey, what are you doing?
嘿 嘿！你们要干什么？
Put me down!
放我下去
Alright, this one is on you.
好了  这个交给你
- Easy! - Sorry!
小心-抱歉！
Stay where you are!
站住不许动
That's my girl.
干得漂亮
Recon.
侦查
Screw this! I'm out of here!
这是什么鬼 我不干了
What the hell is that?
这是什么玩意儿
Hey.
嘿
I'm sorry.
对不起
I never should have trusted him.
我不该相信他的
You do what you thought was right.
你只是做了你认为对的事
I love you.
我爱你
We should find Evelyn.
我们得找到伊芙琳
Come on.
走吧
Serum Status: Ready.
血清准备就绪
Now.
现在
If you press that button,
如果你按下按钮
We're complete safe inside the vault.
我们在地下室是绝对安全的
And...
而且
No one else will ever know what happen to them.
没人知道发生了什么
Your choice.
自己选吧
Initialize: Serum vaporization
血清气化启动
Guys. Guys. They just initiated the serum.
伙计们 他们启动了血清气化程序
Did you find a way to shut it off?
找到关闭方法了吗
Not yet.
还没有
This way.
这边走
It's locked.
锁住了
I'll see if I can get into the Control room.
我看看能不能从控制室打开它
Evelyn, you have to stop this right now.
伊芙琳 你现在必须马上关了它
I...
我
I do want to do this, but I have to.
我本不想这样 但我别无选择
I'm the only one who knows how to save Chicago.
我是唯一知道如何拯救芝加哥的人
I was right to close the gate, but no one listened!
我关上城门是对的 但是没有人听
No one!
没有人
Not even you.
连你也不听
The Allegiant, brought this on themselves.
这都是忠诚者他们逼我这么干的
Evelyn, that serum is not just going to wipe the memories of the Allegiant.
伊芙琳 记忆血清不光会清除忠诚者们的记忆
It's going to do it to the whole city.
还会清除所有人的记忆
What?
什么
Whatever they told you was a lie.
那些人是骗你的
What...
我没有
- Come on - Evelyn.
我不能 伊芙琳
I want to stand by your side.
我来是想帮你的
But what you do to the city...
如果城市被你毁了
... you do to me.
我也一样
Mom.
妈妈
Tobias.
托比亚斯
I won't know who you are.
我会想不起你是谁
Don't do it.
停手吧
Please.
求你了
Going.
快点儿
No!
不
That's why he picked a guy like me for a job like this.
你选择我这样的真是个明智之举
I hope you're watching, David!
我希望你正在看着 大卫
Cristina, have you figured out the door yet?
克瑞斯蒂娜 找到开门的方法了吗
Once it's locked from the inside, the door won't open.
门一旦从里面上锁就打不开了
Well, keep trying!
再试试
Begin serum release.
开始释放血清
Don't breathe it in! Don't breathe in the gas!
不要吸入这些气体
Caleb, we're running out of option here!
凯勒布 我们现在走投无路了
Hold on. I think I found something.
淡定 我想我找到办法了
There's a choke point where the vapor gets pumped out.
这儿有个气体扩散的咽喉点
Cut their comm line to the ship.
切断他们之间的无线电
Caleb?
凯勒布
- Caleb? - Tris?
凯勒布 翠丝
Tris, can you hear me?
翠丝 听得到吗
Caleb!
凯勒布
I'm going in.
我要进去了
What!
卧槽
Oh shit!
我了个大槽
What the...
什么情况
- Make it stop! - It's locked!
快关上它 锁住了
- Open the door! - Open the door!
开门呐 开门呐
Peter, open the door!
彼得 快开门呐
I will find you, Peter.
彼得 我会抓住你的
Tobias.
托比亚斯
You're okay.
没事儿了
Damn it!
该死
- Can you stop it? - No.
能关掉吗 不行
Caleb, do you hear me?
凯勒布 听得到吗
Caleb, where are you?
凯勒布 你死哪儿去了
Caleb Prior!
凯勒布·普勒特
Sorry.
抱歉
Keep going. Stay with me.
继续走 跟上
Tris, look at this. It's really smart.
翠丝 看看这个 非常精确
So, they ran the pipe into the air duck.
它们顺着通风管在空气中扩散
Caleb, focus. Just tell me where it is.
凯勒布 说重点 薄弱点在哪儿
It's right here. There's an isolation valve that controls the flow of the air.
就在这儿 这儿有个独立阀门控制空气流通
But, I don't know how you're going to get down there.
但我不知道怎么去那儿
I do. Four!
我来 老四
Go!
行动
Tris, it's at the end of the hall.
翠丝 在走廊的尽头
Close the doors.
关门
Tris, I control everything.
翠丝 我控制着一切事物
I can even seal the room you're in right now.
我甚至能立刻把你锁在这个房间里
Just stop fighting.
直到你停止反抗
There's another way. Down the stairs.
还有一条路 下楼梯
This is foolish, just stop. I made you.
蠢蛋 快停下吧 我造就了你
You might as well be my child. Which is what you're acting like.
你就像我的孩子一样 你现在的一举一动
A spoil child.
淘气的没边儿了
Tris, at the end of the hall. There's another way on the left.
翠丝 在走廊的尽头 有另一条路通往梯子那儿
It's over, Tris.
都结束了 翠丝
Searching target.
搜索目标
Target identified.
目标已确认
There you are.
找到了
You're right, David. It is over.
大卫 你说得对 都结束了
NO!
不
Serum release halted.
血清释放终止
How's that for "damaged".
缺陷者表现如何
Clear.
安全
It's clear.
干净了
It's not here.
气体没了
Clear.
安全
We did it.
成功了
That's what you do for family.
这才是该为家人做的
Caleb, there's one more thing I want you to do.
凯勒布 我想让你再帮我做件事儿
I want to send a message to David.
我想给大卫发条信息
My name Tris Prior.
我是翠丝·普勒尔
And I'm here to reveal the truth.
我今天在这儿要揭露一个真相
There are others who exist on this planet
这个星球上确实有其他人类存在
They do not view us as equals.
可他们没有平等对待我们
They called themselves the "Pure", and they called us the "damaged".
他们称自己为纯净者 称我们为缺陷者
They created a wall to divide us from their world.
他们用围墙将我们与他们隔离开来
And factions to divide us from each other.
用派系将我们彼此分开
Hello! Come on!
有人吗 得了吧
You think you can ditch me like this?
你认为这样就能够把我一脚踢开是吗
You got me to do your dirty work
让我帮你做那些缺德事儿
and then just, wiped me away like the rest of them!
然后像甩他们一样把我甩掉
We had a deal, pal!
我们不是说好了吗 朋友
We're their experiment, and it almost destroyed us.
我们成了试验品 这几乎毁了我们
I set the autopilot right for our friend's neighbourhood.
我把自动驾驶仪设在了我们朋友附近
Along with a little surprise when it goes through the camouflage wall.
当它穿越伪装墙的时候 会给他们一个小小的惊喜
They tried to make us forget who we are
他们企图让我们忘记自己是谁
and where we're from, but they did not succeed.
来自何方 但他们没有成功
So, here we stand together,
所以我们能站在这儿团结一致
not as 5 factions, but as one city.
不是作为五大派系 而是作为一座城市
We're gonna tear down their wall.
我们要推翻他们建立的围墙
Hey. What's going on?
嘿 那是什么玩意儿
I want the penthouse!
我想住顶楼
Yeah, that's right!
是的 没错
Or...
或者
a room in that really cool upstairs area.
跟上面一样酷的房间也行
Okay, look!
好吧 听着
I'll even take my old bunk back!
我会回到我以前住的地方的
Just come on and open the damn door!
只要快点儿把这该死的门打开
Please!
求你了
You've seen us, and now, we see you.
过去你们看着我们 现在我们看着你们
To those of you beyond the wall,
墙外的人们
hear me loud and clear, because I know you are listening.
你们现在听好了 我知道你们正在听
Chicago is not your experiment.
芝加哥不是你们的实验室
It is our home.
是我们的家园
And it always will be.
永远都是